Remember, remember The 5th of November
The gunpowder treason and plot
I know of no reason Why the gunpowder treason
Should ever be forgot
But what of the man?
I know his name was Guy Fawkes
and I know in 1605, he attempted to blow up the Houses of Parliament
But who was he really?
What was he like?
We are told to remember the idea and not the man
Because a man can fail.
He can be caught, he can be killed and forgotten.
But 400 years later
an idea can still change the world.
I have witnessed firsthand the power of ideas.
I've seen people kill in the name of them
and die defending them.
But you cannot kiss an idea
cannot touch it or hold it
Ideas do not bleed. They do not feel pain.
They do not love.
And it is not an idea that I miss.
It is a man.
A man that made me remember the 5th of November.
A man that I will never forget.
片名：《V怪客》
So I read that the former United States is so desperate for medical supplies
that they have allegedly sent several containers filled with wheat and tobacco.
A gesture, they said, of goodwill.
You wanna know what I think?
Well, you're listening to my show, so I will assume you do.
It's high time we let the colonies know what we really think of them.
I think it's payback time for a little tea party they threw for us a few hundred years ago.
I say we go down to those docks tonight and dump that crap
where everything from the Ulcered Sphincter of Ass-erica belongs!
Who's with me? Who's bloody with me?!
Did you like that?
U.S.A., Ulcered Sphincter of Ass-erica. I mean, what else can you say?
Here was a country that had everything, absolutely everything
and now, 20 years later, is what?
The world's biggest leper colony. Why?
Godlessness.
Let me say that again.
It wasrt the war they started. It wasrt the plague they created.
It was Judgment.
No one escapes their past. No one escapes Judgment.
You think he's not up there?
You think he's not watching over this country?
How else can you explain it? He tested us, but we came through.
We did what we had to do.
Islington. Enfield. I was there. I saw it all.
Immigrants, Muslims
homosexuals, terrorists.
Disease-ridden degenerates. They had to go.
Strength through unity. Unity through faith.
I am a God-fearing Englishman, and I'm goddamn proud of it!
That's quite enough of that, thank you very much.
Oh, shit.
A yellow-coded curfew is now in effect.
Any unauthorized personnel will be subject to arrest.
This is for your protection.
A yellow-coded curfew is now in effect.
Any unauthorized personnel will be subject to arrest.
This is for your protection.
-Excuse me.  -Sorry, I didn't see you
-In a hurry, are we?  -I was just
-It's past curfew, you know.   -My uncle, he's very sick.
-Sick uncle? What you think on that, Willy?  -It's a load of bollocks.
I made a mistake. I shouldn't be out after curfew. I know that.
Maybe you could look after us before getting back to your uncle.
See, my friend, he's kind of sick. Ain't you?
Real sick. Bad case of the blues. You can feel them.
-Don't touch me!  -Look, Willy, kitty's got claws.
-She just threatened us.  -That she did, that she did.
You know what that means, don't you?
It means that we exercise our own judicial discretion.
And you get to swallow it.
-You're Fingermen.  -She's getting the picture.
No, please, I didn't know. I'm sorry.
Not yet you're not. But you will be.
By sunup, if you're not the sorriest piece of ass in all of London
then you'll certainly be the sorest.
Oh, God, no. Please don't do this.
I'll go home. I won't do it again, I swear! Please!
-What do you think, lads?  -Spare the rod, spoil the child.
Help me! Someone help!
The multiplying villainies of nature do swarm upon him.
-What the hell?!  -Bugger off!
Disdaining fortune, with his brandish'd steel
which smoked with bloody execution.
We're Fingermen, pal.
Jesus Christ! Mercy!
We are oft to blame in this 'Tis too much proved.
That with devotiors visage and pious action we do sugar o'er the devil himself.
-What's that mean?  -Spare the rod.
I can assure you, I mean you no harm.
-Who are you?  -Who?
Who is but the form following the function of what
and what I am is a man in a mask.
-Oh, I can see that.  -Of course you can.
I'm not questioning your powers of observation.
I'm merely remarking upon the paradox of asking a masked man who he is.
-Right.   -But on this most auspicious of nights
permit me then, in lieu of the more commonplace sobriquet
to suggest the character of this dramatis persona.
Voila!
In view, a humble vaudevillian veteran
cast vicariously as both victim and villain by the vicissitudes of fate.
This visage, no mere veneer of vanity
is a vestige of the vox populi, now vacant, vanished.
However, this valorous visitation of a bygone vexation stands vivified
and has vowed to vanquish these venal and virulent vermin vanguarding vice
and vouchsafing the violently vicious and voracious violation of volition.
（力量来自团结 团结来自信仰）
The only verdict is vengeance, a vendetta
held as a votive not in vain, for the value and veracity of such
shall one day vindicate the vigilant and the virtuous.
Verily, this vichyssoise of verbiage veers most verbose.
So let me simply add that it's my very good honor to meet you
and you may call me V.
Are you, like, a crazy person?
I am quite sure they will say so.
But to whom, might I ask, am I speaking?
-I'm Evey  -Evey?
E-vey. Of course you are.
-What does that mean?  -It means that I, like God
do not play with dice and do not believe in coincidence.
Are you hurt?
No, I'm fine.
-Thanks to you.  -Oh, I merely played my part.
-But tell me, do you enjoy music, Evey?  -I suppose.
You see, I'm a musician of sorts
and on my way to give a very special performance.
What kind of musician?
Percussion instruments are my speciality.
But tonight I intend to call upon the entire orchestra for this event
and would be honored if you could join me.
I don't think so. I should be getting home.
I promise you, it'll be like nothing you've ever seen.
And afterwards, you'll return home safely.
All right.
It's beautiful up here.
A more perfect stage could not be asked for.
I don't see any instruments.
Your powers of observation continue to serve you well.
But wait. It is to Madame Justice that I dedicate this concerto
in honor of the holiday she seems to have taken from these parts
and in recognition of the imposter that stands in her stead.
Tell me, do you know what day it is, Evey?
-November the 4th?  -Not anymore.
Remember, remember The 5th of November
The gunpowder treason and plot
I know of no reason Why the gunpowder treason
Should ever be forgot
First, the overture.
Yes.
Yes, the strings.
Listen carefully, can you hear it?
Now the brass.
I can hear it!
Look outside, Mommy! They're playing music!
-How do you do that?  -Wait.
Here comes the crescendo!
How beautiful, is it not?
Gentlemen, you have had four hours. You had better have results. Mr. Creedy.
The Bailey area is quarantined.
All significant witnesses have been detained.
Good. Mr. Etheridge?
A recording device was found wired into the central emergency-broadcast system.
The DCD was Tchaikovsky's 1812 Overture.
Add it to the blacklist. I never want to hear that again.
Yes, sir.
We also doubled our random sweeps and are monitoring phone surveillance
indicating a high percentage of conversation concerned with the explosion.
Mr. Dascomb, what are we doing about that?
We're calling it an emergency demolition.
We have spin coverage on the network and throughout the InterLink.
Several experts have been lined up to testify against the Bailey's structural integrity.
I want Prothero to speak on the dangers of these old buildings
and how we must avoid clingingto the edifice of a decadent past.
He should conclude that the New Bailey will become the symbol of our time
and the future that our conviction has rewarded us.
Mr. Heyer.
Our surveillance cameras captured several images of the terrorist
though the mask obviously makes retinal identification impossible.
We also managed to get a picture of the girl that Creedy's men were detaining.
-Who is she, Mr. Finch?  -Not sure yet, sir.
-But we're working on several leads.  -Anything else?
We located the fireworks launch
and found traces of the explosives used at both sites.
Unfortunately it appears that despite the heavy level of sophistication
these devices were homemade with over-the-counter chemicals
making them very difficult to trace.
Whoever he is, chancellor, he's very good.
Spare us your professional annotations, Mr. Finch. They are irrelevant.
Apologies, chancellor.
Gentlemen, this is a test.
Moments such as these are matters of faith.
To fail is to invite doubt into everything we believe
everything we have fought for.
Doubt will plunge this country back
into chaos, and I will not let that happen.
Gentlemen, I want this terrorist found
and I want him to understand what terror really means.
England prevails.
-You think people will buy this?  -Why not?
This is the BTN.
Our job is to report the news, not fabricate it.
That's the government's job.
On the lighter side of things
seems that the crew responsible for the demolition of the Old Bailey
wanted to give the old girl a grand, albeit improvised, sendoff.
Although the demolition had been planned for some time
the music and the fireworks were, according to the crew chief
-"definitely not on the schedule."  -We'll be right back.
Do you believe that load of bollocks? I mean, there was no bloody demolition.
I saw it, the whole thing.
-Did you see it?  -No. Last night I was
Yeah, that's right. You went to see Daddy Deitrich, didn't you?
Evey, there you are.
-You are still working for me.  -Sorry, Patricia.
I need two espressos and three coffees.
And Deitrich is ready for his tea.
I don't get it.
Why does he wear a Guy Fawkes mask? Didrt Fawkes try to blow up Parliament?
It's not too late. He's still got another 16 hours.
Maybe he's just getting started.
Yeah?
Okay. A lead on the girl.
Look, don't get me wrong, I love it. A cow getting crucified.
It's hysterical. But you'll never get it approved.
You've got to rewrite it, okay? Gotta go.
I don't recall getting stood up by a more attractive woman.
-Mr. Deitrich  -Gordon, please.
I don't need "mister" to make this body feel any older.
Gordon
I was on my way last night, but there were Fingermen
and I got scared and went home.
Sadly, after last night, I think our curfew will only get worse.
Gotcha.
-Hey, Fred.  -All that been x-rayed?
Nope. They're filled with bombs.
Well, wait till commercials to set them off, okay?
-I can't believe you watch that shit.  -What?
Laser Lass is banging.
What's all that?
Not sure. They just arrived. Marked for Stage 3.
Must be Prothero.
I wish someone had the balls to tell that brat this station ain't his playground.
What the hell is this?
Just put them over there until I can figure out what they're for.
This looks serious. Her parents were political activists.
-They were detained when she was 12.  -What happened to her?
Juvenile Reclamation Project
-for five years.  -Shit.
We're gonna need backup, but keep it minimal.
You sure about that, sir?
I want a chance to talk to her before she disappears into one of Creedy's black bags.
Who's that?
Don't piss me about. You show me ID, or I'll get Storm Saxon on your ass.
Fucking hell.
Come on, let's move!
You two, cover these elevators. The rest of you follow me.
Attention. Attention.
Will all personnel please evacuate the building.
This is not a drill.
Will all personnel evacuate the building.
What the hell's going on?
-It's jammed.  -Break it down.
Dominic!
Police! Out of the way!
Get out the way!
Damn it!
I'll tell you what I know. I'll tell you what I know.
I'll tell you what I know. England prevails.
-Clear the halls.  -Sir.
Help, Storm, help!
Don't touch it.
Dad, what's wrong with the telly?
Good evening, London.
-Allow me first to apologize  -That's the emergency channel!
I do, like many of you, appreciate the comforts of the everyday routine
the security of the familiar, the tranquility of repetition.
Bloody hell.
I enjoy them as much as any bloke. But in the spirit of commemoration
Who's that, Mum?
Whereby important events of the past
usually associated with someone's death or the end of some awful, bloody struggle
are celebrated with a nice holiday
I thought we could mark this November the 5th
a day that is, sadly, no longer remembered
by taking some time out of our daily lives to sit down and have a little chat.
There are, of course, those who do not want us to speak.
Let me think, let me think.
Even now, orders are being shouted into telephones
and men with guns will soon be on their way.
-It's Chancellor Sutler.  -Damn it!
Why? Because while the truncheon may be used in lieu of conversation
words will always retain their power.
Words offer the means to meaning
and, for those who will listen, the enunciation of truth.
And the truth is
there is something terribly wrong with this country, isn't there?
You designed it, wanted it foolproof. You said every television in London!
Cruelty and injustice, intolerance and oppression.
And where once you had the freedom to object
to think and speak as you saw fit
you now have censors and surveillance coercing your conformity
-and soliciting submission.  -Cameras. We need cameras.
How did this happen? Who's to blame?
Certainly there are those who are more responsible than others.
And they will be held accountable.
But again, truth be told, if you're looking for the guilty
you need only look into a mirror.
I know why you did it.
I know you were afraid.
Who wouldn't be? War, terror, disease.
There were a myriad of problems which conspired
to corrupt your reason and rob you of your common sense.
Fear got the best of you.
And in your panic, you turned to the now High Chancellor Adam Sutler.
He promised you order, he promised you peace
and all he demanded in return was your silent, obedient consent.
-Inspector, they're almost through.  -Last night, I sought to end that silence.
Last night, I destroyed the Old Bailey
to remind this country of what it has forgotten.
More than 400 years ago, a great citizen wished to imbed the 5th of November
forever in our memory.
His hope was to remind the world that fairness, justice and freedom
are more than words.
They are perspectives.
So if you've seen nothing
if the crimes of this government remain unknown to you
then I would suggest that you allow the 5th of November to pass unmarked.
But if you see what I see
if you feel as I feel, and if you would seek as I seek
then I ask you to stand beside me, one year from tonight
outside the gates of Parliament.
And together, we shall give them a 5th of November
that shall never, ever be forgot.
Kerosene fog. He's using our smoke machines.
Cover the exits.
No one gets out. The rest of you, follow me.
Left.
You go right.
Spread out.
Don't shoot! Please don't shoot!
Hold your fire!
He put masks on all of us.
Jesus.
-Don't shoot!  -Wait!
-Wait!  -Hold your fire!
Freeze! Nobody move!
If you're wearing a mask, get down on your knees!
-Get their masks off.  -Please hurry!
There's a bomb in the control booth.
Oh, no.
-Jones, get anyone not wearing a mask out.  -Yes, sir.
-Marshal, help carry this man.  -Sir.
Everyone else, let's go.
Good God.
Hurry up, you lot! Come on! Everybody out!
Dascomb.
Have you any idea how long it would take to rebuild this facility?
Do you have any idea what you're doing?
Wait, wait!
Don't shoot me, please! It's him! It's him!
On your knees! On your knees!
Please! Please don't hurt me!
Here we go.
I did it.
Freeze!
Get your hands on your head. Do it now or I shoot.
I must say that I am rather astonished by the response time of Londors finest.
I hadrt expected you to be quite so Johnny-on-the-spot.
We were here before you even started. Bad luck, chummy.
I don't know about that.
We're interrupting your regularly scheduled program to bring you this terrifying report
of a terrorist takeover of Jordan Tower which ended only moments ago.
A psychotic terrorist, identified only as the letter V
attacked the control booth with high-powered explosives and weapons
that he used against unarmed civilians in order to broadcast a message of hate.
We've just received this footage of a daring police raid.
Stop! Stop, stay where you are, or we'll shoot! Stay where you are!
Now, this is only an initial report
but at this time, it's believed that during this heroic raid
the terrorist was shot and killed.
Bollocks.
Again, from what we've been told by authorities, the danger is now over.
The terrorist is dead.
Right there. What's he thinking?
Is he considering leaving her?
After she just saved him?
He's a terrorist. You can't expect him to act like you or me.
Some part of him's human.
And, for better or worse, she's stuck with him.
-You scared me  -My apologies.
-Are you feeling all right?  -Yes, thank you.
-What is this place?  -It's my home.
-I call it the Shadow Gallery.  -It's beautiful.
-Where did you get all this stuff?  -Oh, here and there.
Much of it from the vaults of the Ministry of Objectionable Materials.
-You stole them?  -Heavens, no.
Stealing implies ownership.
You can't steal from the censor. I merely reclaimed them.
God, if they ever find this place
I suspect if they do, a few bits of art will be the least of my worries.
You mean, after what you've done.
God, what have I done?
I Maced that detective. Why did I do that?
-You did what you thought was right.  -No, I shouldn't have done that.
I must have been out of my mind.
Is that what you really think, or what they'd want you to think?
I think I should go.
-May I ask where?  -Home. I have to go home.
They're looking for you. If they know where you work, they know where you live.
-I have friends, I could stay with them.  -I'm afraid that won't work either.
You have to understand, Evey, I didn't want this for either of us
but I couldn't see any other way.
You were unconscious and I had to make a decision.
If I had left you there, right now you'd be in one of Creedy's interrogation cells.
They'd imprison you, torture you, and, in all probability, kill you
in the pursuit of finding me.
After what you did, I couldn't let that happen
so I picked you up and carried you to the only place I knew you'd be safe:
Here, to my home.
I won't tell anyone, I swear. You know you can trust me.
I'm sorry, but I can't take that risk.
But I don't even know where this is.
You know it's underground. You know the color of the stone.
-That'd be enough for a clever man.  -Are you saying that I have to stay here?
Only until I'm done. After the 5th, I no longer think it'll matter.
You mean a year from now?
I have to stay here for a year?
Sorry, Evey. I didn't know what else to do.
You should've left me alone.
Why didn't you just leave me alone?!
-Anything else on the parents?  -Yeah, it ain't good.
They were interned at Belmarsh.
-Oh, no.  -Yeah.
She died in a hunger strike. He died when the military retook the shed.
And that ain't the worst of it. Her brother was at St. Mary's.
-Christ.  -It's nothing but bad luck here.
So we know her story. Now we need his.
V?
（法语）
I just wanted to apologize for my reaction last night.
I understand what you did for me, and I want you to know I am grateful.
Your hands.
Yes.
There, that's better.
I hope I didn't put you off your appetite.
-No, please. It's just  Are you all right?  -Yes, yes, yes, I'm fine.
Can I ask what happened?
There was a fire. A long time ago.
Ancient history, for some.
Not really very good table conversation.
Now, would you care for a cup of tea with your egg?
-Yes, thank you. I'm starving, actually.  -Have a seat.
-It's delicious.  -Good.
God, I haven't had real butter since I was a little girl.
Where did you get it?
A government supply train on its way to Chancellor Sutler.
-You stole this from Chancellor Sutler?  -Yes.
You're insane.
I dare do all that may become a man. Who dares more is none.
-Macbeth.  -Very good.
My mum, she used to read all his plays to me
and ever since, I've always wanted to act.
Be in plays, movies.
When I was 9, I played Viola in Twelfth Night. Mum was very proud.
Where is your mother now?
She's dead.
I'm sorry.
-Can I ask about what you said on the telly?  -Yes.
-Did you mean it?  -Every word.
You really think blowing up Parliament's going to make this country a better place?
There's no certainty, only opportunity.
You can be pretty certain that if anyone does show up
Creedy'll black-bag every one of them.
People should not be afraid of their governments.
Governments should be afraid of their people.
And you'll make that happen by blowing up a building?
The building is a symbol, as is the act of destroying it.
Symbols are given power by people.
Alone, a symbol is meaningless, but with enough people
blowing up a building can change the world.
I wish I believed that was possible.
But every time I've seen this world change, it's always been for the worse.
I'll tell you what I know. I know this is not a man.
-What is he?  -A man does not wear a mask.
-What is he?  -A man does not threaten innocent civilians.
He's what every gutless, freedom-hating terrorist is:
A goddamn coward!
There will be no negotiation.
When I arrive in the morning, the Paddy will be gone.
I'm looking at the tape right now, and he has no idea how to light me.
My nose looks like Big fucking Ben.
Listen to me, you bleeding sod, England prevails because I say it does!
So does every lazy cunt on this show, and that includes you.
Find another DOP or find yourself another job.
I'll tell you what I wish.
I wish I'd been there.
I wish I'd had the chance for a face-to-face.
Just one chance, that's all I'd need.
This so-called V and his accomplice, Evey Hammond
neo-demagogues, spouting their message of hate.
A delusional and aberrant voice delivering a terrorist's ultimatum.
An ultimatum that was met with swift and surgically precise justice.
-No mercy!  -The moral, ladies and gentlemen, is:
Good guys win, bad guys lose
and, as always, England prevails!
Holy Christ! Jesus!
Good evening, Commander Prothero.
Oh, my God! How did you get in here?
Don't worry, I've made sure our reunion won't be disturbed by
any pesky late-night phone calls, commander.
Stop. Why do you keep calling me that?
That was your title, remember? When we first met, all those years ago.
You wore a uniform in those days.
（拉克希尔拘留所）
You.
-It is you.  -The Ghost of Christmas Past.
-Yeah?  -Finch, it's Dascomb.
-Dascomb.  -I've already called the chancellor.
-We have to get control of the situation.  -What situation?
Chancellor Sutler agreed, for obvious reasons, we have to keep this discreet.
In the wrong light, the loss of the Voice of London
could be devastating to our credibility.
Perhaps a stroke?
No, no, it's too horrific.
A quiet, dignified death in his sleep.
-We got any eyes or ears on this?  -No, camcos were cut.
It's the same m.o. As before. But we got an elevator log ID.
-Let me guess.  -She's in deep, inspector.
V?
My fat, metal friend.
Mondego.
Oh, God. I hope I didn't wake you.
No, I just thought you were fighting. I mean, for real.
My favorite film:
The Count of Monte Cristo, with Robert Donat as Edmond Dantes.
It is not my sword, Mondego, but your past that disarmed you.
It gets me every time.
-Never seen it.  -Really?
-Would you like to?  -Does it have a happy ending?
As only celluloid can deliver.
Okay.
Put the sword away.
Forensics just wrapped.
No prints, no hair, no fibers. The guy is like a ghost.
You won't believe what they found on Prothero.
-Drugs?  -Could've started his own hospital.
-Interesting.  -Why?
Did you know Lewis Prothero was one of the richest men in the country
before he was the Voice of London?
-Drugs?  -Legal ones.
Major stockholder in Viadoxic Pharmaceutical.
Viadoxic and St. Mary's in less than a week. Coincidence?
When you're at this as long as I've been, you stop believing in coincidence.
May we come up?
-You find your own tree.  -You find your own tree.
-Did you like it?  -Yeah.
-But it made me feel sorry for Mercedes.  -Why?
Because he cared more about revenge than he did about her.
Nationwide were devastated as news of the most popular
Wait. What's this?
Most awarded stars in the history of the BTN
a man known to the entire nation as "The Voice of London"
passed away late last night from apparent heart failure.
-She's lying.  -How do you know?
She blinks a lot when she does a story  she knows is false.
It came as no surprise to those who knew him
that his body was at his office
where he often worked long hours after everyone else had gone home.
Lewis, you will be sorely missed.
V, yesterday I couldn't find my ID.
You didn't take it, did you?
Would you prefer a lie or the truth?
Did you have anything to do with that?
-Yes, I killed him.  -You
-Oh, God.  -You're upset.
I'm upset? You just said you killed Lewis Prothero.
I might have killed the Fingermen that attacked you. I heard no objection.
-What?  -Violence can be used for good.
-What are you talking about?  -Justice.
Oh, I see.
There's no court in this country for men like Prothero.
And are you going to kill more people?
Yes.
Take a look at this.
Prothero's military record.
What do you see?
Iraq, Kurdistan, Syria,
before and after, Sudan.
-Busy boy.  -But after all that
they put him in charge of a detention facility at Larkhill.
Well, no good deed goes unpunished.
You think there's a connection between our boy and Larkhill?
It might explain the connection between him and the Hammond girl.
Problem is, I can't find any other record of it.
Larkhill? Larkhill? I cannot recall that particular facility, inspector.
-You're welcome to review our records.  -We've been through your records.
All it says is that there was a detention facility at Larkhill
approximately 10 miles north of Salisbury.
Well, there you have it.
This is a matter of some urgency, major.
We need to know if there was anything different about this facility.
I'm sorry, inspector, I simply cannot recall.
Was there a specific profile for those being sent there?
-Usual undesirables, I should think.  -But do you know?
-Of course not. I wasrt stationed there.  -Do you know who was?
I cannot recall specific names, but if you look through our records
Your records are either deleted, omitted or missing.
As head of the Detention Program at that
Before you go any further, let me remind you things were very chaotic back then.
Now we don't have the problems we had back then.
We all did what we had to do.
And in those circumstances, we did the best we could.
That's all I have to say about that.
You can do this.
（戈登 阿尔伯里街北1号）
Hi.
I've been thinking
There's something I want to ask you
but I don't think you'll understand why unless you know a few things about me.
My father was a writer. You would have liked him.
He used to say artists used lies to tell the truth
while politicians used them
to cover the truth up.
A man after my own heart.
He always told the best stories.
Until my brother died.
That was when everything changed.
My brother was one of the students at St. Mary's.
After he died, my parents became political.
They protested the war and the Reclamation.
When Sutler was appointed high chancellor, they were at the riot in Leeds.
I watched on the television
thinking I was going to see my parents killed.
I remember them arguing at night.
Mum wanted to leave the country. Dad refused.
He said if we ran away, they would win.
Win, like
it was a game.
Evey, quick, hide!
-Mummy!  -Evey!
I never saw them again.
It was like those black bags erased them from the face of the earth.
I'm sorry, Evey.
No, I'm the one that's sorry.
Sorry I'm not a stronger person.
Sorry I'm not like my parents.
I wish I was
but I'm not.
I wish I wasrt afraid all the time
but I am.
I know this world is screwed up. Believe me, I know it better than most.
Which is why I wanted to ask, if there is anything I can do to help make it right
please let me know.
If you wish.
Do you really think you'll find something here?
Worth a shot.
One thing is true of all governments:
The most reliable records are tax records.
It appears that the original electronic records have all been lost.
Probably during the Reclamation. A lot of things went missing back then.
But I found this hard copy filed in the cold vault.
Everything we've got on Larkhill is in there.
Thanks. This is a great help.
（拉丁文）
"By the power of truth, I, while living, have conquered the universe."
-Personal motto?  -From Faust.
That's about trying to cheat the devil, isn't it?
It is. And speaking of the devil
I was wondering if your offer to help was still standing.
-Of course.  -It appears unforeseen circumstances
have accelerated my original plan.
As a result, I'm in need of someone with some theatrical skill.
I'll do my best.
I believe you will.
Another doctor. Why does a detention facility need so many doctors?
I don't know, but this is interesting.
The highest-paid person at the camp was a priest.
-Really?  -Yeah, Father Lilliman.
-Lilliman.  -Was paid almost 200 grand a month.
Now, that is interesting.
Looks like he was promoted. He's a bishop now.
-Your Grace.  -Oh, Denis.
-Has everything been arranged?  -Yes.
I've just received your InterLink itinerary.
You should arrive in Perth in time for Mass.
You're most diligent, Denis
a noble example for all those who labor in the name of our Lord, but
-Your Grace?  -It wasrt labor I was speaking of.
It was, rather, my final remittance that I was interested in.
My last little joy.
I'm sorry, Your Grace.
She has arrived, but there was some confusion at the agency.
They've sent a new girl who, I'm afraid, is a little older than usual.
Older?
Oh, dear. She's not too old, I trust?
That is for Your Grace to decide.
-Oh, my.  -Your Grace.
To think that I doubted your loveliness for an instant.
Mea culpa, my child.
Mea culpa.
Your Grace, we don't have much time and I have to tell you something.
A confession? I love the confessional game.
Tell me your sins.
This isn't a game, Your Grace.
Someone's coming.
I think he means to kill you.
-I'm sorry?  -I'm telling you this
because I want some kind of protection or amnesty.
I had nothing to do with the Bailey and made a mistake in the Jordan Tower.
-I think this should balance it out.  -What are you talking about?
I'm Evey Hammond. I'm
I've been the prisoner of the terrorist V for the past several weeks.
I'm telling you that any moment, he's going to come through that door.
I unlocked the window in the room where Denis told me to get ready.
Wonderful!
It's a game I've never played!
What a delightful mind you have. I hope the rest of you is just as interesting.
-No, please, you have to believe me.  -Oh, I do, I do, I do.
Let me show you the firmness of my beliefs.
Stop it! Get off of me!
Seems I've captured a dangerous terrorist.
Now, how best to procure her confession?
You little bitch. You fucking little whore!
-Reverend.  -Oh, my God.
She wasrt lying. It is you.
I'm sorry.
-I had to.  -Evey!
And thus I clothe my naked villainy
with old odd ends stolen forth from holy writ
and seem a saint, when most I play the devil.
Oh, please, have mercy.
Oh, not tonight, Bishop.
Not tonight.
Don't do this, I beg of you.
Well, then. Childrers hour at the abbey.
Open your mouth and stick out your tongue.
-What the ?  -I don't want to die!
This is Surveillance 109. We have an emergency.
Run every name in that file. I want the whereabouts of all of them.
-Tonight.  -Yes, sir.
Pucker up, here comes the Finger.
Yeah. Get going. I'll handle him.
Creedy.
What are you doing here?
Several prominent party members have been murdered, chief inspector.
This is no ordinary situation and requires more than your ordinary attention.
The chancellor demanded my immediate involvement.
It'll be hard to investigate if you're detaining all my witnesses.
The security of information is paramount.
In these volatile times
mistakes like Jordan Tower can no longer be tolerated
if, indeed, Jordan Tower was an accident.
-What does that mean?  -Terrorist seems to have
a rather intimate understanding of our system.
The chancellor suspects there might be an informer.
Are you saying I'm under surveillance, Mr. Creedy?
At this time, it would behoove you
to cease any investigation of matters that have long since passed
and concentrate on the concerns of our present.
You mean Larkhill?
Major Wilson is a friend of the high chancellor.
-His loyalty is not in question.  -But mine is?
Your mother was Irish, wasrt she?
Terrible what St. Mary's did to Ireland, wasrt it?
I've been a party member for 27 years.
If I were you, chief inspector
I'd find the terrorist
and I'd find him soon.
Please.
Evey? Good God!
I'm sorry. I didn't know where else to go.
Yes, well, you better come inside before someone sees you.
-Cheers.  -I know every cop's looking for me.
I know it's horrible of me to put you in this situation.
-Evey  -You could be in terrible trouble.
Evey, listen to me.
If the government ever searched my house, you would be the least of my problems.
You trusted me.
It would be terrible manners for me not to trust you.
Oh, my God. That's God Save the Queen.
My parents took me to it when they hung it at Gallery 12.
-I thought Sutler had it destroyed.  -He believes he did.
Cost me more than this house, but no matter how bad I feel
it always cheers me up.
-What is that?  -It's a copy of the Koran, 14th century.
-Are you a Muslim?  -No, I'm in television.
But why would you keep it?
I don't have to be Muslim to find the images beautiful, poetry moving.
Is it won'th it? If they found that here
I told you, you'd be the least of my worries.
Thank you, Gordon.
-Thank you so much.  -It's all right.
This whole thing started the night he blew up the Old Bailey.
I was on my way here, and
Yes.
You see, we are both fugitives in our own way.
-But  -You're wondering why
you were invited here to supper in the first place
if my appetites were for less conventional fare.
Unfortunately, a man in my position is expected to entertain
young and attractive ladies like yourself.
Because in this world, if I were to invite who I desired
I would undoubtedly find myself without a home, let alone a television show.
-I'm sorry.  -Not as sorry as I am.
The truth is, after so many years
you begin to lose more than just your appetite.
You wear a mask for so long, you forget who you were beneath it.
I'm sorry, chief inspector. Same basic toxicology as Prothero.
You could get these poisons from any house in London.
Thanks, Delia.
Any leads on finding this guy?
Nothing yet. But there's something else you can help me with.
You started as a botanist, didn't you?
It's  It's a Scarlet Carson.
They're believed to be extinct.
He leaves them at the crime scenes.
I'd appreciate it if you could have a look at it.
Any information could be helpful.
Of course.
Excuse me.
Yeah?
I just finished going through the file, inspector. You better get back here.
Yeah, okay.
-My God. He's killed them all.  -All but one.
-Who is she?  -Not sure.
She's clearly one of the people in charge at Larkhill.
But after they shut it down, she disappeared for two years.
Till she applied for an overseas visa, which was denied.
Running away?
Probably, because after that, all record of her seems to stop.
-She changed her name.  -That's what I'm guessing.
I put a call in to the registry, but I haven't heard back.
-It's late, or early.  -Call them again. I want that name.
What? Are you sure about that?
Okay. Thank you.
Dr. Diana Stanton changed her name to Delia Surridge.
-The coroner?  -Yeah.
Jesus, I just saw her.
It's you, isn't it?
-You've come to kill me.  -Yes.
Thank God.
I'm sorry, I can't get a response from that number.
There's a problem with the connection.
Jesus Christ.
He's there.
After what happened, after what they did
I thought about killing myself.
But I knew that one day you'd come for me.
I didn't know what they were going to do.
I swear to you.
Read my journal.
What they did was only possible because of you.
Oppeneimer was able to change more than the course of a war.
He changed the entire course of human history.
Is it wrong to hold on to that kind of hope?
I have not come for what you hoped to do.
I've come for what you did.
It's funny.
I was given one of your roses today.
I wasrt sure you were the terrorist until I saw it.
What a strange coincidence, that I should be given one today.
There are no coincidences, Delia.
Only the illusion of coincidence.
I have another rose.
And this one is for you.
-You're going to kill me now?  -I killed you 10 minutes ago
while you slept.
-Is there any pain?  -No.
Thank you.
Is it meaningless to apologize?
Never.
I'm so sorry.
Damn it.
The terrorist obviously wanted us to have it.
He wanted us to know the story, or at least a part of it.
Am I to understand that you have read this document, inspector?
-Yes, sir.  -Has anyone else read it?
-No, sir.  -Then let me make this perfectly clear to you.
The contents of this document are a matter of national security
constituting an assault on the character of several important party members
as well as a blatant violation of the Articles of Allegiance.
As the authenticity of this document cannot be verified
it could be an elaborate forgery created by the terrorist
as easily as it could be the deranged fantasy of a former party member
who resigned for psychological reasons.
Any discussion of this document or its contents
will be regarded, at the very least, as an act of sedition
if not a willful act of treason.
-Is that understood, Mr. Finch?  -Yes, sir.
You would do well, inspector
to put it out of your mind.
May 23rd.
My first batch of subjects arrived today
and I have to admit that I'm very excited.
This could be the dawn of a new age.
Nuclear power is meaningless
in a world where a virus can kill an entire population
and leave its wealth intact.
-Stay together!  -Come on, move!
May 27th.
Commander Prothero toured the lab with a priest, Father Lilliman
who I was told is here to monitor for Rules and Rights violations.
It made me nervous, but the commander assured me there wouldn't be a problem.
June 2nd.
I keep wondering if these people knew how they might be helping their country
if they would act any differently.
They're so weak and pathetic. They never look you in the eye.
I find myself hating them.
August the 18th.
Of the original four dozen, over 75 percent are now deceased.
No controllable pattern has yet emerged.
September the 18th.
There is one case that continues to give me hope.
He exhibits none of the immune-system pathologies the other subjects developed.
I've discovered cellular anomalies in his blood that I've been unable to categorize.
The mutations seem to have triggered
the abnormal development of basic kinesthesia and reflexes.
The subject said he could no longer remember
who he was or where he was from.
Whoever he was, he is now the key to our dream
and the hope that all of this will not have been in vain.
November the 5th.
It started last night, around midnight.
The first explosions tore open the entire medical section.
All my work, gone.
I was trying to understand how it could've happened when I saw him.
The man from room 5.
He looked at me.
Not with eyes. There were no eyes.
But I know he was looking at me because I felt it.
Oh, God
what have I done?
（法语）
What is that you're making?
We called it "eggie in the basket." My mum made them.
-This is weird.  -What?
The first morning I was with him, he made me eggs just like this.
-Really?  -I swear.
That is a strange coincidence. Although there's an obvious explanation.
-There is?  -Yes, Evey.
I am V.
At last you know the truth.
You're stunned, I know.
Hard to believe, isn't it, that beneath this wrinkled, well-fed exterior
there lies a dangerous killing machine with a fetish for Fawkesian masks.
That is not funny, Gordon.
Yeah, I know. I'm useless without a studio audience.
I've seen people go to jail for less than that.
Of course, he was right, wasrt he?
There is something wrong with this country.
（恐怖分子发动生物攻击）
（圣玛丽病毒已造成178人死亡）
（三河水厂遭感染）
（大瘟疫）
（国王医院发生暴动）
（八万人丧生）
Morning, inspector.
You're at it early.
Is something wrong? You don't look so good, sir.
I wanna ask a question, Dominic.
I don't care if you answer me or not.
I just wanna say this aloud.
But I need to know that this question will not leave this office.
Yeah, of course, inspector, but
Because of the terrorist?
No.
So, what is it, chief? What's going on?
The question I want to ask is about St. Mary's
and Three Waters.
The question that's kept me up for the last 24 hours
the question I have to ask, is:
What if the worst
the most horrifying biological attack in this country's history
was not the work of religious extremists?
Well, I don't understand. We know it was. They were caught. They confessed.
And they were executed. I know.
And maybe that's really what happened.
But I see this chain of events
these coincidences, and I have to ask:
What if that isn't what happened? What if someone else unleashed that virus?
What if someone else killed all those people?
Would you really wanna know who it was?
Sure.
Even if it was someone working for this government?
That's my question.
If our own government was responsible
for what happened at St. Mary's and Three Waters
if our own government was responsible for the deaths of almost 100,000 people
would you really wanna know?
This has to be the bloody coldest March in years.
Keep talking like that, we'll lose our party status.
-They're a pack of lying, greedy hypocrites!  -Keep it down, will you?
（力量来自团结  团结来自信仰）
Based on random audio sweeps, I've projected that right now
80 percent of the public believe the terrorist is still alive.
We're also showing a 12-percent increase
over last month's positive mention in all four quadrants.
-Mr. Creedy?  -We're handling it as best we can.
Arrests are as high as they've been since the Reclamation.
I want more than arrests. I want results.
-What's all this about?  -I'm celebrating.
Celebrating what?
I think this could be the best show we've ever done.
Very good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
Listen, we've got an extraordinary show for you tonight.
You're not gonna believe it. As a matter of fact, I don't think I do.
Will you please give a very warm welcome
to our own Chancellor Adam Sutler!
-No way!  -No, it can't be!
We threw out the censor-approved script and shot one I wrote this morning.
Oh, my God.
Chancellor, chancellor, chancellor
I understand you've been under tremendous strain lately
since the beginning of this whole terrorism business
and we thought it would be a nice idea to try and help you relax. Girls?
Warm milk. There's nothing better.
I understand you enjoy a glass every night, chancellor.
Since I was a boy.
But you're wrong, Mr. Deitrich.
-The terrorist was never a serious concern.  -Oh, really?
-Chancellor, chancellor  -It's him.
Are you saying that he's not still alive and active?
The terrorist has been neutralized.
Oh, my God! Chancellor, look!
The terrorist!
Get him!
Oh, dear.
At last!
And now, for all the world to see.
It's him!
Unand me! I am your chancellor!
How dare you! I am the chancellor!
Imposter!
Soldiers! That man is the terrorist!
-I order you to shoot that traitor!  -Liar!
-Faker!  -Fraud!
-Ready!  -Aim!
-Fire!  -Fire!
What are they gonna do, fine us?
Big deal. We've got the most-watched show on air.
Well, you're my agent, that's what I pay you for.
Protect me.
I should've hired him to be my mother.
-You're mad.  -Either that or I wasrt breast-fed.
-Is everything a joke to you?  -Only the things that matter.
-What if they come after you?  -I tell you what's gonna happen.
I'll have to make some kind of apology, do some boring fundraiser.
In the meantime, our ratings will go through the roof. It'll be fine. Trust me.
Gordon?
Quick, Evey, hide!
Not so funny now, is it, funnyman?
-Gotcha.  -No, no.
Do you know why you're here, Evey Hammond?
Please.
You've been charged with three counts of murder
the bombing of government property, conspiracy to commit terrorism
treason and sedition, the penalty for which is death by firing squad.
You have one chance, and only one chance, to save your life.
You must tell us the identity or whereabouts
of code name V.
If your information leads to his capture
you will be released from this facility immediately.
Do you understand what I'm telling you?
You can return to your life, Miss Hammond.
All you have to do is cooperate.
Process her.
I know there's no way I can convince you this is not one of their tricks
but I don't care.
I am me.
My name is Valerie.
I don't think I'll live much longer, and I wanted to tell someone about my life.
This is the only autobiography that I will ever write and
God. I'm writing it on toilet paper.
I was born in Nottingham in 1985.
I don't remember much of those early years, but I do remember the rain.
My grandmother owned a farm in Tottle Brook
and she used to tell me that God was in the rain.
I passed my 11 Plus and went to girls' grammar.
It was at school that I met my first girlfriend.
Her name was Sarah.
It was her wrists.
They were beautiful.
I thought we would love each other forever.
I remember our teacher telling us
that it was an adolescent phase that people outgrew.
Sarah did.
I didn't.
In 2002, I fell in love with a girl named Christina.
That year I came out to my parents.
I couldn't have done it without Chris holding my hand.
My father wouldn't look at me. He told me to go and never come back.
My mother said nothing.
But I'd only told them the truth. Was that so selfish?
Our integrity sells for so little, but it is all we really have.
It is the very last inch of us.
But within that inch
we are free.
It ends whenever you want it to.
-Just tell us where he is.   -I don't know.
I'd always known what I wanted to do with my life
and in 2015 I starred in my first film, The Salt Flats.
It was the most important role of my life. Not because of my career
but because that was how I met Ruth.
The first time we kissed
I knew I never wanted to kiss any other lips but hers again.
We moved to a small flat in London together.
She grew Scarlet Carsons for me in our window box
and our place always smelt of roses.
Those were the best years of my life.
But America's war grew worse and worse, and eventually came to London.
The bill proposed by the Undersecretary for Defense, Adam Sutler
to close the remaining tube stations passed with
After that, there were no roses anymore.
Not for anyone.
You won't last much longer.
You're gonna die here.
Why protect someone who doesn't give a shit about you?
I remember how the meaning of words began to change.
How unfamiliar words like "collateral" and "rendition" became frightening
while things like "Norsefire" and the "Articles of Allegiance" became powerful.
I remember how "different" became dangerous.
I still don't understand it
why they hate us so much.
They took Ruth while she was out buying food.
I've never cried so hard in my life.
It wasrt long till they came for me.
It seems strange that my life should end in such a terrible place.
But for three years, I had roses and apologized to no one.
I shall die here.
Every inch of me shall perish.
Every inch
but one.
An inch.
It is small, and it is fragile
and it is the only thing in the world won'th having.
We must never lose it or give it away. We must never let them take it from us.
I hope that, whoever you are, you escape this place.
I hope that the world turns and that things get better.
But what I hope most of all is that you understand what I mean
when I tell you that even though I do not know you
and even though I may never meet you
laugh with you, cry with you
or kiss you
I love you.
With all my heart
Valerie.
I'm instructed to inform you that you have been convicted by special tribunal
and that unless you are ready to offer your cooperation, you are to be executed.
Do you understand what I'm telling you?
-Yes.  -Are you ready to cooperate?
-No.   -Very well.
Escort Miss Hammond back to her cell.
Arrange a detail of six men
and take her out behind the chemical shed and shoot her.
It's time.
I'm ready.
Look, all they want is one little piece of information.
Just give them something, anything.
Thank you
but I'd rather die behind the chemical sheds.
Then you have no fear anymore. You're completely free.
What?
Hello, Evey.
You.
-It was you?  -Yeah.
That wasrt real?
-Is Gordon ?  -I'm sorry, but Mr. Deitrich's dead.
I thought they'd arrest him
but when they found a Koran in his house, they had him executed.
Oh, God.
-Fortunately, I got to you before they did.  -You got to me?
You did this to me?
You cut my hair?
You tortured me?
You tortured me.
Why?
You said you wanted to live without fear.
I wish there'd been an easier way
-but there wasrt.  -Oh, my God.
I know you may never forgive me
but nor will you understand how hard it was for me.
Every day, I saw in myself everything you see in me now.
Every day, I wanted to end it.
But each time you refused to give in, I knew I couldn't.
You're sick! You're evil!
You could have ended it. You could have given in, but you didn't.
-Why?  -Leave me alone! I hate you!
That's it! See, at first, I thought it was hate too.
Hate was all I knew. It built my world, imprisoned me
taught me how to eat, how to drink, how to breathe.
I thought I'd die with all the hate in my veins.
But then something happened.
It happened to me just as it happened to you.
Shut up! I don't want to hear your lies!
Your own father said that artists use lies to tell the truth.
Yes, I created a lie.
But because you believed it, you found something true about yourself.
-No  -What was true in that cell is true now.
What you felt in there has nothing to do with me.
I can't feel anything anymore!
Don't run from it, Evey. You've been running all your life.
I can't  Can't breathe.
Asthma. When I was little
Listen to me, Evey.
This may be the most important moment of your life. Commit to it.
They took your parents from you. They took your brother from you.
They put you in a cell and took everything they could take except your life.
And you believed that was all there was, didn't you?
The only thing you had left was your life, but it wasrt.
-Oh, please.  -You found something else.
In that cell, you found something that mattered more to you than life.
When they threatened to kill you unless you gave what they wanted
you told them you'd rather die.
You faced your death, Evey.
You were calm. You were still.
Try to feel now what you felt then.
Oh, God.
I felt
Yes?
I'm dizzy.
I need air.
Please, I need to be outside.
There's a lift. It'll take us to the roof.
God is in the rain.
V.
I'm leaving.
There are 872 songs in here.
I've listened to them all, but I've never danced to any of them.
-Did you hear me?   -Yes.
I can't stay here.
I know.
Well, you won't find any more locked doors here.
I thought about keeping this
but it didn't seem right, knowing you wrote it.
I didn't.
May I show you something before you go?
《盐沼》
-She was real.  -Yes.
She's beautiful.
-Did you know her?  -No.
She wrote the letter just before she died.
And I delivered it to you as it had been delivered to me.
Then it really happened, didn't it?
-Yes.  -You were in the cell next to her.
And that's what this is all about.
You're getting back at them for what they did to her.
-And to you   -What was done to me created me.
It's a basic principle of the universe
that every action will create an equal and opposing reaction.
Is that how you see it?
-Like an equation?  -What was done to me was monstrous.
And they created a monster.
-Do you know where you'll go?  -No.
That would have scared me before
but I suppose I should thank you.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Evey
may I ask you for something?
If I had one wish, I would wish to see you again, if only once
before the 5th.
-All right.  -Thank you.
Chancellor, I know no one seems to want to discuss this
but if we're to be prepared for any eventuality
then it can't be ignored any longer.
The red report in front of you has been vetted by several demolition specialists.
Now, it concludes that
the most logical delivery system for the terrorist to use
would be an airborne attack.
A separate report has been filed
suggesting a train, despite the fact that the tunnels surrounding Parliament
have been sealed shut.
Who filed that report?
Chief Inspector Finch.
Do you have any evidence to support this conclusion, Mr. Finch?
No, sir. Just a feeling.
If I am sure of anything, inspector
it is that this government will not survive if it is to be subject to your feelings.
Mr. Dascomb, what we need right now
is a clear message to the people of this country.
This message must be read in every newspaper
heard on every radio, seen on every television.
This message must resound throughout the entire InterLink!
I want this country to realize that we stand on the edge of oblivion.
I want every man, woman and child to understand how close we are to chaos.
I want everyone
to remember why they need us!
In the former United States, civil war continues to devastate the Midwest.
Scientists attribute this water shortage to the lack of rainfall the last two years.
Ministry officials expect water coupon prices to rise.
Police have arrested nine suspects
Can you believe this shit? Been going on all summer.
Outside the quarantine zone, a new airborne pathogen has killed 27 people.
Authorities uncovered new evidence linking the terrorist organization called V
to the St. Mary's viral attack on London 14 years ago.
My friend inside the Finger came up with something.
There were three men.
Covert intel.
Original black-baggers, all under Creedy.
Alan Percy, Robert Keyes, William Rookwood.
The day after the St. Mary's outbreak
Percy gives his Beretta a blowjob, Keyes dies in a fire
Rookwood goes missing.
Bloody coincidences are making me sick to my stomach.
Rookwood.
How do I know that name?
Shit
He must have had a hidden trip on his file at the Finger.
But how'd he know it was you?
What do we do?
I'm a cop. I have to know.
I came when they opened it. It gave me the collywobbles.
Still does.
That's close enough, inspector.
We're not wired.
I'm sorry, but a man in my position survives by taking every precaution.
-You have information for us?  -No, you already have the information.
All the names and dates are inside your head.
What you want, what you really need, is a story.
A story can be true or false.
I leave such judgments to you, inspector.
Our story begins, as these stories often do
with a young, up-and-coming politician.
He's a deeply religious man and a member of the Conservative Party.
He's completely single-minded and has no regard for the political process.
The more power he attains, the more obvious his zealotry
and the more aggressive his supporters become.
Eventually, his party launches a special project in the name of national security.
（拉克希尔拘留所）
At first it's believed to be a search for biological weapons
and it's pursued without regard to its cost.
However, the true goal of this project is power.
Complete and total hegemonic domination.
The project, however, ends violently.
But the efforts of those involved are not in vain
for a new ability to wage war is born from the blood of one of the victims.
Imagine a virus, the most terrifying virus you can
and then imagine that you and you alone have the cure.
But if your ultimate goal is power, how best to use such a weapon?
Well, it's at this point in our story that along comes a spider.
A man seemingly without a conscience
for whom the ends always justify the means.
He suggests that their target should not be an enemy of the country
but rather, the country itself.
Three targets are chosen to maximize the effect of the attack:
A school, a tube station and a water-treatment plant.
Several hundred die within the first few weeks.
Three Waters has, in fact, been contaminated.
Authorities are attempting to control its deadly spread.
Sent destruction through the Underground.
Fueled by the media, fear and panic spread quickly
fracturing and dividing the country until, at last, the true goal comes into view.
Before the St. Mary's crises
no one would have predicted the results of the election that year. No one.
And then not long after the election, lo and behold, a miracle.
Some believed it was the work of God himself.
But it was a pharmaceutical company controlled by certain party members
that made them all obscenely rich.
A year later, several extremists are tried, found guilty and executed
while a memorial is built to canonize their victims.
But the end result, the true genius of the plan, was the fear.
Fear became the ultimate tool of this government.
Through it, our politician was ultimately appointed
to the newly created position of high chancellor.
The rest, as they say, is history.
-Can you prove any of this?  -Why do you think I'm still alive?
All right. We'd like to take you into protective custody, Mr. Rookwood.
I'm sure you would.
But if you want that recording, you'll do what I tell you to do.
Put Creedy under 24-hour surveillance.
When I feel safe he can't pick his nose without you knowing
I'll contact you again.
Till then, cheerio.
Rookwood
why didn't you come forward before?
What were you waiting for?
Well, for you, inspector.
I needed you.
What's he doing in the dark there?
Creepy Creedy. Not sure I wanna know.
Sutler can no longer trust you, can he, Mr. Creedy?
And we both know why.
After I destroy Parliament
his only chance will be to offer them someone else, some other piece of meat.
And who will that be?
You, Mr. Creedy.
A man as smart as you has probably considered this.
A man as smart as you probably has a plan.
That plan is the reason Sutler no longer trusts you.
It's the reason why you're being watched right now
why there are eyes and ears in every room of this house
-and a tap on every phone.  -Bollocks.
Oh, a man as smart as you, I think, knows otherwise.
-What do you want?  -Sutler.
Come, now, Mr. Creedy, you knew this was coming.
You knew that one day it'd be you or him.
That's why Sutler's been kept underground for security purposes.
That's why there are several of your men close to Sutler
men that can be counted on. All you have to do is say the word.
-What do I get out of this deal?  -Me.
If you accept, put an X on your front door.
Why should I trust you?
Because it's the only way you're ever going to stop me.
It is not my sword, Mondego, but your past that disarmed you.
May we come up?
You find your own tree.
We got Creepy pinned like a butterfly for weeks.
Still no word. What's he waiting for?
Yeah? Inspector, it's for you.
-Yeah.  -Is that Chief Inspector Finch?
-It is.  -This is Captain Clark
of the 137th Ward at Southend.
-We found him.  -Found who?
William Rookwood, the one you're looking for.
I saw your report a couple weeks back, thought I'd run it through our John Does.
I hooked him. Perfect dental match.
A floater. Fishermen picked him up. No ID, never solved. Till now, that is.
-William Rookwood is dead?  -I'd say so. Twenty years now.
Goddamn it!
That son of a bitch sat there
and spoon-fed me that bullshit, and I ate it up!
So, what do we do now, inspector?
We do what we should have been doing.
We find him.
Every day, gentlemen.
Every day that brings us closer to November
every day that man remains free
is one more failure.
Three hundred and forty-seven days, gentlemen.
Three hundred and forty-seven failures!
Chancellor, we do not have the adequate force
We are being buried beneath the avalanche of your inadequacies, Mr. Creedy!
I'll get it.
-Eric Finch?  -Yeah.
Bloody hell.
How many went out?
So far we count eight boxcars.
-Several hundred thousand, at least.  -Christ.
I want anyone caught with one of those masks arrested!
Give me the money! Give me the fucking money!
We're under siege here. The whole city's gone mad.
-This is exactly what he wants.  -What?
-Anarchy in the UK!  -Chaos.
Mr. Creedy, I am holding you personally responsible for this situation.
The problem is that he knows us better than we know ourselves.
That's why I went to Larkhill last night.
-That's outside quarantine.  -I had to see it.
There wasrt much left.
But when I was there, it was strange.
I suddenly had this feeling that everything was connected.
Like I could see the whole thing.
One long chain of events that stretched all the way back before Larkhill.
I felt like I could see everything that had happened
and everything that was going to happen.
Hey, you!
It was like a perfect pattern laid out in front of me
and I realized that we were all a part of it
and all trapped by it.
So do you know what's gonna happen?
No. It was a feeling.
But I can guess.
With so much chaos, someone will do something stupid.
And when they do
things will turn nasty.
Rioters were arrested in Brixton.
And then Sutler will be forced to do the only thing he knows how to do.
At which point, all V needs to do is keep his word.
And then
Tonight's your big night.
You ready for it?
Are we ready for it?
I missed this song.
I didn't think you'd come.
I said I would.
You look well.
Thank you.
May I inquire as to how you've avoided detection?
A fake ID works better than a Guy Fawkes mask.
I must confess, every time I heard a siren, I worried about you.
I worried about myself for a while.
But then, one day, I was at a market
and a friend, someone I had worked with at the BTN, got in line behind me.
I was so nervous that when the cashier asked me for my money, I dropped it.
My friend picked it up
and handed it to me.
She looked at me right in the eyes
didn't recognize me.
Whatever you did to me worked better
than I'd have imagined.
I have a gift for you, Evey
but before I give it to you, I'd like to ask you something.
Would you dance with me?
Now? On the eve of your revolution?
A revolution without dancing is a revolution not won'th having.
I'd love to.
Tonight, I will speak directly to these people
and make the situation perfectly clear to them.
The security of this nation depends on complete and total compliance.
Tonight, any protestor, any instigator or agitator
will be made example of!
Chancellor, there is a contingency that has not been addressed.
And what is that, Mr. Dascomb?
-Should the terrorist succeed  -He won't.
I understand that it is highly unlikely, but if he does
If he does, and something happens to that building
the only thing that will change,
the only difference it will make
is that tomorrow morning, instead of a newspaper
I will be reading Mr. Creedy's resignation!
You've been busy. They're very scared right now.
I heard Sutler's going to make a public statement tonight.
It's nearly time.
The masks were ingenious.
It was strange to suddenly see your face everywhere.
Conceal me what I am, and be my aid
for such disguise as haply shall become the form of my intent.
-Twelfth Night.  -Viola.
-I don't understand.  -What?
How you can be one of the most important things that has happened to me
and yet I know almost nothing about you.
I don't know where you were born, who your parents were
if you had any brothers or sisters.
I don't even know what you really look like.
Evey, please.
There is a face beneath this mask
but it's not me.
I'm no more that face than I am the muscles beneath it
or the bones beneath them.
I understand.
Thank you.
There isn't much time.
I have something I must give you.
I went by Parliament.
Never seen anything like it. Tanks, anti-aircraft, infantry.
Makes you wish that no one would show up tonight.
But if they do, what do you think will happen?
What usually happens when people without guns
stand up to people with guns.
Pull over here.
We've searched these tunnels for weeks. You think you're gonna find him now?
Inspector.
It's all gone wrong, hasn't it?
The Underground? I thought they closed this all down.
They did.
It took nearly 10 years to clear the tracks and lay a bit of my own.
Let me show you.
These tracks lead to Parliament.
Yes.
Then it's really going to happen, isn't it?
It will if you want it to.
-What?  -This is my gift to you, Evey.
Everything that I have: My home, my books, the gallery, this train
I'm leaving to you to do with what you will.
Is this another trick, V?
No. No more tricks. No more lies.
Only truth.
And the truth is, you made me understand that I was wrong
that the choice to pull this lever
is not mine to make.
-Why?  -Because this world
the world that I'm a part of and
that I helped shape, will end tonight.
And tomorrow, a different world will begin
that different people will shape,
and this choice belongs to them.
Where are you going?
The time has come for me to meet my maker
and to repay him in kind for all that he's done.
V, wait!  Please, you don't have to do this.
You could let it go. We could leave here together.
No. You were right about what I am.
I have no tree waiting for me.
All I want, all I deserve, is at the end of that tunnel.
That's not true.
I can't.
My fellow Englishmen
tonight, our country
that which we stand for
and all that we hold dear
faces a grave and terrible threat.
The area's clean, sir.
This violent and unparalleled assault to our security
will not go undefended.
Where is he?
Or unpunished.
Penny for the Guy.
Our enemy is an insidious one,
seeking to divide us
and destroy the very foundation of our great nation.
I have kept my side of the bargain, but have you kept yours?
Bring him down.
Tonight we must remain steadfast.
We must remain determined.
But most of all, we must remain united.
Those caught tonight in violation of curfew
will be considered in league with our enemy
and prosecuted as a terrorist without leniency or exception.
I want to see his face.
Tonight I give you my most solemn vow
that justice will be swift
it will be righteous
and it will be without mercy.
Oh, God. No.
At last, we finally meet.
I have something for you, chancellor.
A farewell gift.
For all the things you've done, for the things you might have done
and for the only thing you have left.
Goodbye, chancellor.
Mr. Creedy.
Disgusting.
Now that's done with
it's time to have a look at your face.
Take off your mask.
No.
Defiant to the end, huh?
You won't cry like him, will you? You're not afraid of death.
You're like me.
The only thing you and I have in common, Mr. Creedy, is we're both about to die.
How do you imagine that's gonna happen?
With my hands around your neck.
Bollocks.
What are you gonna do, huh?
We've swept this place. You've got nothing.
Nothing but your bloody knives and your fancy karate gimmicks.
We have guns.
No, you have bullets
and the hope that when your guns are empty I'm no longer standing
because if I am
you'll all be dead before you've reloaded.
That's impossible!
Kill him.
My turn.
Die! Die!
Why won't you die?!
Why won't you die?
Beneath this mask there is more than flesh.
Beneath this mask there is an idea, Mr. Creedy.
And ideas are bulletproof.
This is perimeter one. Whitehall is secure. Over.
This is General Ackroyd.
Keep communication tight.
I won't have this getting any more bollixed up than it already is.
V!
Oh, God, we have to stop your bleeding.
Please, don't. I'm finished and glad of it.
Don't say that.
I told you, only truth.
For 20 years I sought only this day.
Nothing else existed
until I saw you.
Then everything changed.
I fell in love with you, Evey
like I no longer believed I could.
V, I don't want you to die.
That's the most beautiful thing
you could have ever given me.
V?
V?!
Eyes and ears have detected movement heading to Trafalgar Square.
This is perimeter one. We have enemy contact.
Hold it. Stop right there.
You're Evey Hammond, aren't you?
Then it's over?
Almost.
Stop. Get your hand off that lever.
No.
Enemy is approaching fast. Requesting orders.
-What shall we do?  -No response from Command.
Or from Party Leader Creedy.
Or from the high chancellor.
Why are you doing this?
-Because he was right.  -About what?
That this country needs more than a building right now. It needs hope.
Bloody hell, stand down! Stand down!
Jesus bloody Christ.
It's time.
Tell me
do you like music, Mr. Finch?
That music?
Yes.
His music.
Who was he?
He was Edmond Dantes.
And he was my father
and my mother.
My brother.
My friend.
He was you
and me.
He was all of us.
No one will ever forget that night
and what it meant for this country.
But I will never forget the man
and what he meant to me.